<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>002.Literature Notes on</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.literature-notes/</link><description>Recent content in 002.Literature Notes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://research.elnad.com/002.literature-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/1chp14-doing-digital-migration-studies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/1chp14-doing-digital-migration-studies/</guid><description>Annotation Summary of 1chp14 doing digital migration studies.pdf. #methodology
see concept.digital diaspora 14.2.2 Paradigm (II) Everyday Digital Migrant Life Highlight [252]: 14.2.2 Paradigm (II) Everyday Digital Migrant Life In contrast with the first paradigm, the second paradigm is non-digital-media-centric as it takes online-offline relationships as its main unit of analysis. Rather than taking digital practices as a starting point, in this strand scholars combine fieldwork in physical places with observing digitally mediated practices.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2017.nguyen-tien-Vietnam-and-Its-Diaspora-An-Evolving-Relationship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2017.nguyen-tien-Vietnam-and-Its-Diaspora-An-Evolving-Relationship/</guid><description>see tien nguyen Extracted Annotations (2022-01-26) Vietnam and Its Diaspora: An Evolving Relationship ( note on p.239) Diaspora PoliciesDue to historical reasons, Vietnam has large communities of overseas Vietnamese in developed countries. T ( note on p.247)</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2019.small-How-Vietnamese-in-the-US-and-beyond-fuel-dreams-with-remittances/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2019.small-How-Vietnamese-in-the-US-and-beyond-fuel-dreams-with-remittances/</guid><description>[[ReadItLater]] [[Article]] see small How Vietnamese in the US and beyond fuel dreams with remittances A Vietnamese investor watches share price activity on a securities trading floor in Hanoi. Photo: AFP
The catalyst for capitalist growth in Vietnam – often dubbed Asia’s next tiger economy – is frequently ascribed to market reforms starting in 1986 and subsequent foreign investment flows. But diaspora capital sent from abroad ­– from those who left the country as refugees and migrants after the end of the war in 1975 – has also contributed significantly to the country’s economic growth over the past 30 years.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Chan-and-Tran-2011-Recycling-Migration-and-Changing-Nationalisms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Chan-and-Tran-2011-Recycling-Migration-and-Changing-Nationalisms/</guid><description>Annotation Summary of Chan and Tran 2011, Recycling Migration and Changing Nationalisms.pdf. Highlight [page 3]: This paper examines the changes in state policies towards overseas subjects and returnees. It argues that the state of origin is an active transnational actor forging a transnational space that accommodates overseas Vietnamese back to the Vietnamese whole. Such state-initiated transnational practices not only tie the diaspora to homeland development, but also construct a pan-Vietnamese discourse aimed at solidifying the Vietnamese nation worldwide.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Diminescu-Loveluck-Paristech-2014-The-connected-migrant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Diminescu-Loveluck-Paristech-2014-The-connected-migrant/</guid><description>Annotation Summary of Diminescu, Loveluck, Paristech - 2014 - The connected migrant From migratory Trajectories To migratory Traceabilities.pdf. Highlight [page 1]: The connecTed migranT: From migraTory TrajecTories To migraTory TraceaBiLiTies All aspects of the migrant experience are affected by the ubiquitous presence of digital technologies. Even before he/she has left, the would-be migrant now usually forms his/her project after a thorough search on Google, rather than after hearing the stories told by those who have returned from emigration.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Homing-An-Affective-Topography-of-Ethnic-Korean-Return-Migration-Ji-Yeon-O.-Jo-z-lib.org/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Homing-An-Affective-Topography-of-Ethnic-Korean-Return-Migration-Ji-Yeon-O.-Jo-z-lib.org/</guid><description>Annotation Summary of Homing An Affective Topography of Ethnic Korean Return Migration (Ji-Yeon O. Jo) Introduction Legacy Migration, Transborder Belongings,and Korean Peoplehood Highlight [2]: As of 2013, there were an estimated 704,536 diaspora Koreans with foreign citizenship residing in South Korea, a 17 percent increase from the previous year. 1 and Note [2]: 17% increase in return migration to south korea in 2013 compared to previous year.
Highlight [2]: Though each of the stories given here is as unique as Inga’s, the diaspora and return migration experiences of these migrants have cumulatively been shaped by colonial and diaspora history, by the ethnic policies of the nation-states in which they have settled, by postcolonial and Cold War geopolitics, and by the pervasive influence of economic and cultural globalization.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Lei-Guo-2020-Conceptualizing-virtual-transnational-diaspora-Returning-to-the-return-of-Chinese-transnational-academics-annotated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Lei-Guo-2020-Conceptualizing-virtual-transnational-diaspora-Returning-to-the-return-of-Chinese-transnational-academics-annotated/</guid><description>Annotation Summary of Lei, Guo - 2020 - Conceptualizing virtual transnational diaspora Returning to the ‘return’ of Chinese transnational academics-annotated.pdf. Note [1]: theoretical lens of transnational dias- pora, our
Note [1]:
fn1-0117196820935995 Highlight [7]: With easier travel and communication, it has become more common for the haigui, literally meaning “sea turtles” (returnees who settle) to become a hai’ou, meaning “seagull,” who can easily migrate between China and other countries. Meanwhile, for those returnees who are relatively immobile, it has also become quite common to maintain various social connections overseas.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Levitt-Glick-Schiller-Transnational-social-fields-annotated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Levitt-Glick-Schiller-Transnational-social-fields-annotated/</guid><description>Annotation Summary of Levitt, Glick-Schiller - 3. Transnational social fields-annotated.pdf. Highlight [page 1]: rethink and Note [page 1]: deterritorialized
Note [page 1]: not within a single nation-state
Note [page 1]: some migrants remain strongly influenced by continuing ties to their home countries that span across national borders
Note [page 1]: Note [page 1]: Note [page 2]: cannot look only at what goes on within national boundaries to understand completely the lives of individuals</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Lie-J-1995-From-international-migration-to-transnational-diaspora.-Contemporary-Sociology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Lie-J-1995-From-international-migration-to-transnational-diaspora.-Contemporary-Sociology/</guid><description>Annotation Summary of 2077625.pdf. p. 304 Highlight [p. 304]: At the same time, transnationalism identifies a multiplicity of migrant networks and communities that transcend received national boundaries. The idea of diaspora-as an unending sojourn across different lands-better captures the emerging reality of transnational networks and communities than the language of immigration and assimilation (see Khachig Th1h1yan&amp;rsquo;s opening essay in Diaspora 1:1, 1991; and Carol Breckenridge and Arjun Appadurai&amp;rsquo;s initial piece in Public Culture 1:1, 1988).</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Nedelcu-Migrants-New-Transnational-Habitus-Rethinking-Migration-Through-a-Cosmopolitan-Lens-in-the-Digital-Age/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Nedelcu-Migrants-New-Transnational-Habitus-Rethinking-Migration-Through-a-Cosmopolitan-Lens-in-the-Digital-Age/</guid><description>Annotation Summary of Migrants New Transnational Habitus Rethinking Migration Through a Cosmopolitan Lens in the Digital Age.pdf. Highlight [1]: ‘inclusive cosmopolitan’
Highlight [3]: The heuristic value of the transnational paradigm resides precisely in its ability to encapsulate the disconnection between state, national, cultural and geographical borders. Furthermore, by deconstructing the territorial equation between state, nation and society, transnational scholarship puts forward serious arguments for changing the lens through which social scientists perceive and analyse the world (Wimmer and Glick Schiller 2002).</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Nedelcu-Online-Migrants/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Nedelcu-Online-Migrants/</guid><description>Annotation Summary of Nedelcu - Unknown - Online Migrants.pdf. 2 Co-presence Routines and Ways of Migrant Multiple Belonging in a Polymedia Environment Highlight [3]: lized identities and biographies and to act at a distance in real time. In the same time, while accelerating integration and incorporation paths in host societies, these practices also allow the defence of particular values and the claim to belonging to a culture of origin while living anywhere in the world (Nedelcu 2010, 2012) and Note [3]: online memberships allow for belonging to any group while living anywhere in the world.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/schiller2005.Transnational-social-fields-and-imperialism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/schiller2005.Transnational-social-fields-and-imperialism/</guid><description>Annotation Summary of schiller2005.Transnational social fields and imperialism.pdf. Highlight [page 2]: Drawing from my ethnographic research with fundamentalist Christians and studies of Haitian long-distance nationalism, I argue that in order to develop a theory of globe-spanning power and society, Transnational Studies must examine the relationship between the transnational social ﬁelds and the contemporary restructuring of imperial power. and Note [page 2]: to develop theory of transnational studies, it needs to include relationship between transnational social fields and contemporary restructuring of imperial power.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Vertovec-2017-transnationalism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Vertovec-2017-transnationalism/</guid><description>Annotation Summary of Vertovec - 2017 - transnationalism.pdf. BOOK COVER Highlight [i]: ‘Transnationalism’ refers to multiple ties and interactions linking people or institutions across the borders of nation-states.
1 INTRODUCTION: TRANSNATIONALISM, MIGRANT TRANSNATIONALISM AND TRANSFORMATION Highlight [2]: or sustained cross-border relationships, patterns of exchange, affiliations and social formations spanning nation-states
Highlight [3]: interactions between national governments (such as formal agreements, conflicts, diplomatic relations), or concerning the toing and fro-ing of items from one nation-state context to another (such as people/travel and goods/trade), we might best retain our description of these practices as</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/yuval-davis-2006-Belonging-and-the-politics-of-belonging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/yuval-davis-2006-Belonging-and-the-politics-of-belonging/</guid><description>Annotation Summary of Belonging and the politics of belonging(1).pdf. Highlight [3]: Even in its most stable ‘primordial’ forms, however, belonging is always a dynamic process, not a reified fixity, which is only a naturalized construction of a particular hegemonic form of power relations. and Note [3]: #belonging as not fixed and a social construct of “particular hegemonic forms of power relations”
Highlight [3]: three major analytical levels on which belonging is constructed.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/yuval-davis-2017-situated-intersectionality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/yuval-davis-2017-situated-intersectionality/</guid><description>Annotation Summary of yuval-davis - 2017 - situated intersectionality.pdf. Highlight [3]: Fundamental to my approach to situated intersectionality analysis (which I started to develop with Floya Anthias (eg, 1983, 1992) in the early 1980’s, before the term intersectionality was invented by Kimberlé Crenshaw in (1989), is that intersectional analysis should be applied to all people and not just to marginalised and racialised women, with whom the rise of intersectionality theory is historically linked (e.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/yuval-davis-wemyss-cassidy-2019-Bordering-etc.-z-lib.org/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/yuval-davis-wemyss-cassidy-2019-Bordering-etc.-z-lib.org/</guid><description>Annotation Summary of Bordering ( etc.) (z-lib.org).pdf. Introduction Highlight [1]: Similarly, borders have been moved away from the territory of their state into the territories of other countries: not only are US border checks taking place in Canadian airports and British ones in Eurostar terminals in continental Europe, but consulates in most countries have effectively turned into passport and visa checkpoints. In this way, the deterritorialisation and reterritorialisation of borders have been taking place globally.</description></item><item><title>010.Literature Review MOCs</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/010.Literature-Review-MOCs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/010.Literature-Review-MOCs/</guid><description>Literature Review MOCs #moc
This is my Map of Contents for my research Total writing: &amp;lt; 80k words (approx. 160 pages single spaced; 320 double) 8 Chapters @ 10k words per chapter · Use analytic expressions to chunk ideas: o Social, psychological, economic, political, cultural, etc o But keep narrative and connect to bigger picture
What I need to write: Social anthropology
Literature review of existing research Research question: Why do the 2nd generation return to their ethnic/ancestral homeland?</description></item><item><title>1994.Basch, Glick Schiller-Nations Unbound</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/1994.Basch-Glick-Schiller-Nations-Unbound/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/1994.Basch-Glick-Schiller-Nations-Unbound/</guid><description>Nations unbound: transnational projects, postcolonial predicaments, and deterritorialized nation-states [[Basch]], Linda G; [[Glick Schiller]], Nina; Szanton Blanc, Cristina
01 d l Page 11 28/10/2021 14:46 images of &amp;ldquo;immigrant&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;migrant&amp;rdquo; different today. no longer anchored in circumstances of ealier historic moments. immigrants now develpp networks, activities, patterns of living, and ideologies that span their home and host societies.
02 d l Page 11 28/10/2021 14:46
03 d l Page 11 28/10/2021 14:47 prior scholars just coined the new evolving idea of immigrants and migrants as &amp;ldquo;[[008.</description></item><item><title>2004.kohPersistentAmbiguitiesVietnamese2004</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2004.kohPersistentAmbiguitiesVietnamese2004/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2004.kohPersistentAmbiguitiesVietnamese2004/</guid><description>[[koh]]
title: Persistent ambiguities: Vietnamese ethnology in the Doi Moi period (1986-2001) authors: Priscilla Koh year: 2004</description></item><item><title>2005.brubaker-Diaspora Diaspora</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2005.brubaker-Diaspora-Diaspora/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2005.brubaker-Diaspora-Diaspora/</guid><description>Extracted Annotations (2021-12-14) p2 &amp;ldquo;proposes to treat diaspora not as a bounded entity but as an idiom, stance and claim.&amp;quot;( Brubaker 2005:2 )
diaspora as NOT a bounded identity but as an idiom, stance, and claim ( note on p.2) p3 &amp;ldquo;Palestinian diaspora, too, has been construed as a &amp;lsquo;catastrophic&amp;rsquo; diaspora/ or in Cohen&amp;rsquo;s (1997) term, a &amp;lsquo;victim diaspora&amp;rsquo;/ on the model of the Jewish case.&amp;quot;(](zotero://open-pdf/library/items/T5QVBU2M?page=2)Brubaker 2005:3)</description></item><item><title>2008.Beck - Mobility and the cosmopolitan perspective-annotated</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2008.Beck-Mobility-and-the-cosmopolitan-perspective-annotated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2008.Beck-Mobility-and-the-cosmopolitan-perspective-annotated/</guid><description>Source [[Attachments/PDFs/already read/Beck - 2008 - Mobility and the cosmopolitan perspective-annotated.pdf]]
Mobility and the cosmopolitan perspective Beck, Ulrich
01 d l Page 2 28/9/2021 3:20 how to do SS research when comparisons aren&amp;rsquo;t fixed and there is a shift from national gaze to cosmopolitan gaze
02 d l Page 2 28/9/2021 3:20
03 d l Page 2 28/9/2021 3:20 normative/philosophical cosmopolitanism: plea for cross-cultural and cross-national harmony
04 d l Page 2 28/9/2021 3:20</description></item><item><title>2008.nguyen.We Return In Order to take leave</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2008.nguyen-We-return-in-order-to-take-leave/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2008.nguyen-We-return-in-order-to-take-leave/</guid><description>Mdnotes File Name: 2008.nguyen-We return in order to take leave We return in order to take leave. natalie nguyen Short summary: initial returnsmultiple returnsthose who did not returnunderlying theme of all returns were &amp;ldquo;family&amp;rdquo;. Vietnam means above all, family&amp;quot; (p. 24)
Extracted Annotations (12/23/2021, 2:43:48 PM)
imaginary undertakings of those who choose not to travel back to Vietnam. The article will examine three factors: howwomen remember the past, how they negotiate the return journey, and the role of memory in their narratives.</description></item><item><title>2014.nguyen-akbarTensionsDiasporicReturn2014</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2014.nguyen-akbarTensionsDiasporicReturn2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2014.nguyen-akbarTensionsDiasporicReturn2014/</guid><description>[[005.Authors/nguyen-akbar mytoan]]
title: The Tensions of Diasporic &amp;lsquo;Return&amp;rsquo; Migration: How Class and Money Create Distance in the Vietnamese Transnational Family authors: Mytoan Nguyen-Akbar year: 2014 Mdnotes File Name: [[nguyen-akbarTensionsDiasporicReturn2014]] Extracted Annotations (2021-10-30) &amp;ldquo;In this article, I examine how these more permanent diasporic &amp;ldquo;return&amp;rdquo; migrations affect the&amp;rdquo; ( Nguyen-Akbar 2014:178 )
&amp;ldquo;durability of extended family relationships, and what this looks like within preexisting webs of filial obligations and perceived expectations of gift giving and migrant reciprocity&amp;rdquo; ( Nguyen-Akbar 2014:179 )</description></item><item><title>2015.koh.You Can Come Home Again</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2015.koh.You-Can-Come-Home-Again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2015.koh.You-Can-Come-Home-Again/</guid><description>Mdnotes File Name: [[kohYouCanCome2015]] Yellow Annotations (2021-10-31) p184 &amp;ldquo;specifically, it can also be understood as an attempt to galvanize Vietnamese identity from something that might be based on region, place of origin or political or class background into a new &amp;ldquo;imagined community&amp;rdquo; (Anderson 2006).&amp;rdquo;
Koh 2015:184
p184 &amp;ldquo;The central message implicit in contemporary state discourse is that overseas Vietnamese remain essentially Vietnamese wherever they are, regardless of when they left the country, or for that matter, whether or not they were born in Vietnam.</description></item><item><title>2015.reed-danahay-Foreigner My Own</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2015.reed-danahay-Foreigner-My-Own/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2015.reed-danahay-Foreigner-My-Own/</guid><description>Mdnotes File Name: [[reed-danahayForeignerMyOwn2015]] Follows both fieldwork and autoethnography of memoirs to reconstruct the cosmopolitainism of viet returnees to VN. accounts of memoirs are from mostly 1.5 generation.
also only focuses on fieldwork done in America.</description></item><item><title>2016.Andrea Svobodová and Eva Janská</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2016.Andrea-Svobodov%C3%A1-and-Eva-Jansk%C3%A1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2016.Andrea-Svobodov%C3%A1-and-Eva-Jansk%C3%A1/</guid><description>Czech Republic Identity Development Among Youth of Vietnamese Descent in the Czech Republic M.L. Seeberg and E.M. Goździak (eds.), Contested Childhoods: Growing up in Migrancy, IMISCOE Research Series, DOI 10.1007/978-3-319-44610-3_7
[[2016.Andrea Svobodová and Eva Janská]]
#Identity and #belonging concept of #migrancy
How do these children label themselves? Viet or Czech?
Research focuses more on process of identity construction rather than &amp;ldquo;identity outcomes&amp;rdquo;
most important driving forces behind actions of immigrant children (2nd gen) are age, gender, education levels, etc.</description></item><item><title>2016.nguyen-akbar.Finding American Dream Abroad</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2016.nguyen-akbar.Finding-American-Dream-Abroad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2016.nguyen-akbar.Finding-American-Dream-Abroad/</guid><description>Mdnotes File Name: [[nguyen-akbarFindingAmericanDream2016]] Yellow Annotations (2021-10-31) p99 &amp;ldquo;with many knowing that, over time, companies and organizations would transition toward hiring their counterparts (the postVietnam War Vietnamese baby boomer elites who were educated abroad) to meet growing demand for skilled workers.&amp;rdquo;
Nguyen-Akbar 2016:99
p101 &amp;ldquo;Ong has written about the privileges of borderless cosmopolitan life for high-skilled migrants,&amp;rdquo;
Nguyen-Akbar 2016:101
p101 &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;flexible citizenship,&amp;rdquo; possessing unequal positions of power in the global economy compared to their local Vietnamese counterparts.</description></item><item><title>2016.nguyen-akbarFindingAmericanDream2016</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2016.nguyen-akbarFindingAmericanDream2016/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2016.nguyen-akbarFindingAmericanDream2016/</guid><description>[[005.Authors/nguyen-akbar mytoan]]
title: Finding the American Dream Abroad? Narratives of Return Among 1.5 and Second Generation Vietnamese American Skilled Migrants in Vietnam authors: Mytoan Nguyen-Akbar year: 2016 Mdnotes File Name: [[nguyen-akbarFindingAmericanDream2016]] Extracted Annotations (2021-10-30) &amp;ldquo;with many knowing that, over time, companies and organizations would transition toward hiring their counterparts (the postVietnam War Vietnamese baby boomer elites who were educated abroad) to meet growing demand for skilled workers.</description></item><item><title>2017. Diasporic Returns to the Ethnic Homeland-Tsuda, Changzoo</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2017.-Diasporic-Returns-to-the-Ethnic-Homeland-Tsuda-Changzoo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2017.-Diasporic-Returns-to-the-Ethnic-Homeland-Tsuda-Changzoo/</guid><description>Diasporic Returns to the Ethnic Homeland: The Korean Diaspora in Comparative Perspective [[tsuda]]
Korean diaspora is notable due to the proportion of diaspora out of the ethnic homeland. Almost 9.5% reside in the diaspora. Viet diaspora only 4.4%. (p. 4)</description></item><item><title>2017.besbris.LessTheoryMore2017a</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2017.besbris.LessTheoryMore2017a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2017.besbris.LessTheoryMore2017a/</guid><description>Mdnotes File Name: [[besbrisLessTheoryMore2017a]] Extracted Annotations (2021-12-14) p147 &amp;ldquo;We stake the position that a theoretically rich landscape, where theories are plentiful, is one wherein ideas are vacuous. Instead, we should aim for a descriptively rich discipline, where our theoretical frameworks are considerably less numerous and therefore more powerful.&amp;quot;( Besbris.Khan 2017:147 )
less theory makes the work more meaningful ( note on p.147) p148 &amp;ldquo;If most papers that use the concept of cultural capital are required to produce a theoretical amendment or reformulation, then the concept quickly becomes so expansive as to be meaningless (see Healy 2017).</description></item><item><title>2017.nguyen-akbar-Formation Spatial Symbolic</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2017.nguyen-akbar-Formation-Spatial-Symbolic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2017.nguyen-akbar-Formation-Spatial-Symbolic/</guid><description>Mdnotes File Name: [[nguyen-akbarFormationSpatialSymbolic2017]] Extracted Annotations (2021-10-30) &amp;ldquo;This study focused on highly skilled returnees, aiming to analyze how transnational flows of capital such as language, education, and access played into the symbolic boundary making and identity politics of return&amp;rdquo; ( Nguyen-Akbar 2017:1115 )
&amp;ldquo;The Overseas Vietnamese returnees in my study reinforced global class inequalities and social boundaries through behaviors such as their residential decisions to live in newly built high-rise apartments in expatriate neighborhoods&amp;rdquo; ( Nguyen-Akbar 2017:1116 )</description></item><item><title>2017.nguyen-akbarFormationSpatialSymbolic2017</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2017.nguyen-akbarFormationSpatialSymbolic2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2017.nguyen-akbarFormationSpatialSymbolic2017/</guid><description>[[005.Authors/nguyen-akbar mytoan]]
title: The Formation of Spatial and Symbolic Boundaries among Vietnamese Diasporic Skilled Return Migrants in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam authors: Mytoan Nguyen-Akbar year: 2017
Mdnotes File Name: [[nguyen-akbarFormationSpatialSymbolic2017]] Extracted Annotations (2021-10-30) &amp;ldquo;This study focused on highly skilled returnees, aiming to analyze how transnational flows of capital such as language, education, and access played into the symbolic boundary making and identity politics of return&amp;rdquo; ( Nguyen-Akbar 2017:1115 )</description></item><item><title>2019.erel-Migrant Capitals Proposing</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2019.erel-Migrant-Capitals-Proposing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2019.erel-Migrant-Capitals-Proposing/</guid><description>Extracted Annotations (2021-12-14) p248 &amp;ldquo;Migrants routinely experience a mismatch between the spatial contexts where their resources were formed and the new contexts where they look to validate these as capitals.&amp;quot;( Erel.Ryan 2019:248 )
p248 &amp;ldquo;Combining the macro-level factors of economic and political structures, the meso-level of networks with the micro-level of personal narratives, the article proposes that such a multi-level analytic framework, that is sensitive to temporal and spatial dynamics, is useful in highlighting the fractures, hierarchies and exclusions in specific fields.</description></item><item><title>2019.Pnina-Working-class cosmopolitans and diaspora</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2019.Pnina-Working-class-cosmopolitans-and-diaspora/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2019.Pnina-Working-class-cosmopolitans-and-diaspora/</guid><description>Source [[Attachments/PDFs/already read/Cohen, Fischer - 2018 - Routledge handbook of diaspora studies-annotated.pdf]]
Working-class cosmopolitans and diaspora Pnina [[005.Authors/Werbner]] in Routledge handbook of diaspora studies Cohen, Robin; Fischer, Carolin
01 d l Page 7 28/10/2021 14:47 02 d l Page 8 28/10/2021 14:47 03 d l Page 8 28/10/2021 14:47 04 d l Page 158 28/10/2021 14:46 equating cosmopolitan with intellectuals. stuart [[005.Authors/hall]] speaks of &amp;ldquo;[[008.Theories and Concepts/cosmopolitainism from below]]&amp;rdquo;. The tendency to associate cosmopolitanism with intellectuals is, of course, not new, and these days includes also so-called ‘capitalist cosmopolitans’ whose passports ‘bear stamps of many countries’ (Calhoun 2002: 87; cf.</description></item><item><title>2019.Tsuda-Diasporacity</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2019.Tsuda-Diasporacity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2019.Tsuda-Diasporacity/</guid><description>Source [[Attachments/PDFs/already read/Cohen, Fischer - 2018 - Routledge handbook of diaspora studies-annotated.pdf]] [[008.Theories and Concepts/concept.diaspora]]
Diasporicity: Relative embeddedness in transnational and co-ethnic networks [[diasporicity]] Takeyuki (Gaku) [[tsuda]] Routledge handbook of diaspora studies Cohen, Robin; Fischer, Carolin
11 d l Page 159 28/10/2021 14:46
12 d l Page 208 28/10/2021 14:46
13 d l Page 209 28/10/2021 14:47
14 d l Page 209 28/10/2021 14:46 whittle down definition of &amp;ldquo;diaspora&amp;rdquo; to 3 criteria.</description></item><item><title>2019.tsudaDiasporicReturnsEthnic</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2019.tsudaDiasporicReturnsEthnic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2019.tsudaDiasporicReturnsEthnic/</guid><description>Mdnotes File Name: [[tsudaDiasporicReturnsEthnic2019]] [[tsuda]] Extracted Annotations (2021-12-14) p14 &amp;ldquo;However, the Korean diaspora has a significant impact on South Korea not only because so many people have left (and continue to leave), but also because a significant number of them have returned. Like other diasporas around the world, the Korean diaspora consists of not only migratory dispersal from the homeland but also a return migration flow from various Korean diasporic communities around the world back to the homeland.</description></item><item><title>2020.Lipman-In Camps Vietnamese Refugees</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2020.Lipman-In-Camps-Vietnamese-Refugees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2020.Lipman-In-Camps-Vietnamese-Refugees/</guid><description>[[lipmanCampsVietnameseRefugees2020]]
Extracted Annotations (2021-12-17) some classified as refugee when they&amp;rsquo;re not. refugee/migrant binary narrative.
South Vietnamese Navy who had been at sea when Saigon fell and whose ships simply never returned to port. Their protests unnerved U.S. officials, who had not anticipated that any Vietnamese would want to return to communist-controlled Vietnam. There ( note on p.10) After 1975, close to 800,000 individuals left Vietnam by boat, survived,and sought refuge in camps in Malaysia, Thailand, Indonesia, the Philippines, and Hong Kong.</description></item><item><title>2020.Nozina and Kraus-Vietnamese Organized Crime in the Czech Republic</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2020.Nozina-and-Kraus-Vietnamese-Organized-Crime-in-the-Czech-Republic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2020.Nozina-and-Kraus-Vietnamese-Organized-Crime-in-the-Czech-Republic/</guid><description>#bookreview
Vietnamese Organized Crime in the Czech Republic Book Reviews In discussion w/ Phi Hong Su 5-6 paragraphs?
1 p overview of book, (dan) This is a short and accessible work on the Vietnamese diaspora, its immigration patterns, and ties to criminality in the Czech Republic (CR). Nozina and Kraus' backgrounds, both as researchers and within the police force, offers readers an intimate insider perspective into the Vietnamese diasporic experience and its connection to crime networks.</description></item><item><title>2020.Yeoh - Serial migration , multiple belongings and orientations toward the future The perspective of middle-class migrants in Sin-annotated</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2020.Yeoh-Serial-migration-multiple-belongings-and-orientations-toward-the-future-The-perspective-of-middle-class-migrants-in-Sin-annotated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2020.Yeoh-Serial-migration-multiple-belongings-and-orientations-toward-the-future-The-perspective-of-middle-class-migrants-in-Sin-annotated/</guid><description>Source [[Attachments/PDFs/already read/Yeoh - 2020 - Serial migration , multiple belongings and orientations toward the future The perspective of middle-class migrants in Sin-annotated.pdf]]
‘middling migrants’, a term which refers to those who occupy the space between transnational elites and low-waged labour migrants.
We argue that focusing on how migrants occupy the transnational social field between origin and destination alone does not fully encapsulate the experiences of serial migrants.
. Cultivated through a search for belonging – being in one place, longing for another (Hedetoft and Hjort, 2002)</description></item><item><title>2021.mullerTransnationalLifeTrajectories</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2021.mullerTransnationalLifeTrajectories/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2021.mullerTransnationalLifeTrajectories/</guid><description>title: Transnational Life Trajectories and the Notion of Return — German-Born Viet Kieu ( Overseas Vietnamese ) authors: Max Müller year: 2021 [[2021.mullerTransnationalLifeTrajectories]]
[[muller]]
Source #statistics #stats numbers of VK returnees to VN The numbers of returning Viet Kieu for tourist activities have increased since economic reforms were initiated by the Vietnamese Communist Party (VCP) in 1986. Whereas in 1990 only around 70,000 Viê.tkiêu returned for short trips or holidays to Vietnam, political reforms and a steadily improving economic situation led those numbers to swell to over one million in 2009 (Schiele 2017: 7).</description></item><item><title>2021.tranEthnicIdentitySecondGeneration2021</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2021.tranEthnicIdentitySecondGeneration2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/2021.tranEthnicIdentitySecondGeneration2021/</guid><description>title: Ethnic Identity among Second-Generation Vietnamese American Adolescents authors: Tham Thi thu Tran, Elizabeth Bifuh-Ambe year: 2021 #readme</description></item><item><title>Allen - smart thinking skills for critical understanding and writing-</title><link>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Allen-smart-thinking-skills-for-critical-understanding-and-writing-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://research.elnad.com/002.Literature-Notes/Allen-smart-thinking-skills-for-critical-understanding-and-writing-/</guid><description>Source [[Attachments/PDFs/already read/Allen - Unknown - smart thinking skills for critical understanding and writing-annotated.pdf]]
is not an ability to find the answers: it is the ability to ask the right questions. If you can as
To distinguish a claim from other sorts of statements, we simply need to consider whether it is possible to ask &amp;lsquo;Is this statement true or false?&amp;rsquo;.
The technical, grammatical names for the two components within a claim are the &amp;lsquo;subject&amp;rsquo; and the &amp;lsquo;predicate&amp;rsquo; of the statement.</description></item></channel></rss>